Hello friends,
today I will discuss this topic,
if a person has
taken a loan from a bank or NFC, then is he
insured, that is, is there any kind of
insurance that if that person
dies, then his loan gets repaid because
generally the question of insurance arises only
when the person taking the loan dies
or he gets afflicted with some disease,
like if he has taken a Kisan Credit Card or a
personal loan, then after all, does he have
insurance or not, so let me clarify one thing to
you that there is
no such insurance, if you have taken a
loan from any bank or PFC, then
you do not get any insurance policy attached to it,
this is against the guidelines of IRDA
and this is against the guidelines of RBI, that is,
when the bank gives you a loan, it
only gives you a loan, it cannot give you any kind of
policy by attaching it to it, no matter
which loan you take,
personal loan, vehicle loan, home loan,
business loan, gold loan,
Kisan Credit Card, all the loans you get do
not have any kind of insurance, so you should know about this  You'll never be under any misconception. If
your bank has given you a loan, you're
insured.
Secondly, when you take out a loan, the bank
can't force you to take out
this insurance. It's
mandatory for the bank to take out this insurance policy. It's your
choice whether you want a term
insurance policy or a loan insurance policy. Now, let's
talk about why an insurance policy, whether it's a
loan insurance policy or a term
insurance policy, is
necessary for a loan holder. Look, you must have
understood by looking at the family picture in the background.
Suppose only one person in a family
earns money and dies due to some reason, then
you can understand
how much financial burden is placed on the family. [
Music] On
top of that, if you have a home loan running and there's
no insurance, you have to
bring it in to save the house. Because
bank officials don't show any humanity in the list, they
immediately
start their paperwork. A
lot of cases like this are seen,
but at the same time, I've noticed that this is a weak
point where many people get a
little down because of their family.  So the agent gets a
chance to mis-sell the insurance policy.
Insurance policy mis-selling means
that any policy on which high commission is given should be sold
to the customer, which is very wrong. Let
me tell you one thing, whether the insurance policy is
of a private bank or a
public sector bank, no insurance policy is
bad, the only need is that it should be given to the
right person for whom the
insurance policy is suitable,
but in today's date, there is a lot of
mis-selling of insurance policy due to high commission. Anyone
gives any policy to anyone
which is not needed at all.
Now, because I will tell you one thing, if
you have taken any loan, then you should get yourself
insured. It is
your own life time insurance. The
simplest thing is that its premium should be
very low.
I have got myself insured for Rs
1 crore. I got one for Rs 70 lakh and
one for Rs 50 lakh, in which my annual installment of Rs 70 lakh
is Rs 11000 and my installment of Rs 50 lakh is
around Rs 6000, which  I have taken a
simple term insurance and have taken some other insurance, so I
believe that whether
you have taken a loan or not, still get a
term insurance. I will
not suggest you the name of any company
that you should buy it only from them, you should go online.
First of all, while buying, remember that you have to
buy it online only, do not buy it from any local agent
because if you buy term insurance
online, then the commission of the local agent gets
reduced, so the term
insurance policy is cheaper. As of
today, the term insurance policy which is a
life insurance company is HDFC
Life,
you can go online on your own and see
which one has a lower premium, which one is suitable for you, which one is
of some other company, but I want
you to take a term insurance policy,
I will not give you any link or any
kind of description for this,
you have to do it yourself, you have to find out
which life term insurance
policy is good for you, you should take it, that is,
I believe that if you are 20 years or
25 years old, then it is possible that you can get a life term insurance policy for Rs 10,000 or Rs 15,000.  If you get a
term plan of crores then
friends, I fully hope that you
liked my video, please
share my video on your WhatsApp group
and keep my channel subscribed for
banking related information,
thank you friends.